usc.edu.au 2019-06-05

# Privacy | University of the Sunshine Coast, Queensland, Australia

The University of the Sunshine Coast collects and uses personal information about its students, staff and others in order to operate effectively, in compliance with [Queensland’s Information Privacy Act (2009).](https://www.legislation.qld.gov.au/view/html/inforce/current/act-2009-014)

Personal information held by the University is collected and managed in a responsible, secure manner, and will not be released to third parties without your consent, unless required by law.

Information on how the University manages personal information can be found in our Information Management Framework - Governing Policy.

#### Website information

When you look at this website, our web server makes a record of your visit and logs the following information for statistical purposes:

  * the type of browser used
  * the date and time of visit to the site
  * the pages accessed and documents downloaded
  * the previous site visited
  * the user's server internet address
  * demographic information about the user including age, gender and web browsing patterns. Individuals cannot be personally identified by this data.

In general, this website does not use cookies. However, some applications and services available from this site may use cookies to track business processes. If you have configured your browser to reject all cookies you are still able to view information only pages on our site.

Cookies are packets of information that uniquely identify your computer as a visitor to this site and can be used to monitor traffic patterns and to serve you more efficiently if you revisit the site. A cookie does not identify you personally but it does identify your computer.

Email correspondence sent to this site may be treated as a public record and retained as required by Queensland’s _Public Records Act (2002)_ and other relevant legislation.

#### Access

An individual has the right under the Information Privacy Act to have access to and amendment of their personal information held by the University.

For more information about access to your personal information, contact the Right to Information and Privacy Coordinator, University of the Sunshine Coast - ML19, Maroochydore DC 4558 or email [RTI@usc.edu.au](mailto:RTI@usc.edu.au).

#### Privacy complaints

If you have concerns about how the University has dealt with your personal information, you are entitled to make a formal complaint. The complaint must be made in writing or by email and sent to the Right to Information and Privacy Coordinator, University of the Sunshine Coast – ML19, Maroochydore DC 4558 or email [RTI@usc.edu.au](mailto:RTI@usc.edu.au) Your complaint will be acknowledged, investigated, and the results of the investigation reported to you in writing.

If you are unsatisfied with the University’s response, you are entitled to refer your complaint to the Queensland Information Commissioner for review. Again, this complaint must be in writing and provide an address for correspondence. The postal address for the Queensland Information Commissioner is: 

Office of the Information Commissioner  
PO Box 10143  
Adelaide Street   
BRISBANE QLD 4000
